Register of the Wladyslaw Anders Collection, 1939-1946.
Hoover Institution Archives
- REPORTS
  - Volume 38
    - Nos. 8,251-8,438 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 8,439-8,569 (Folder 3)
  - Volume 39
    - Nos. 8,571-8,716 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 8,717,8,800 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 40
    - Nos. 8,801-8,924 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 8,925-9,180 (Box 56., Folder 1)
  - Volume 41
    - Nos. 9,181-9,382 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 9,383-9,600 (Folder 3)
  - Volume 42
    - Nos. 9,601-9,792 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 9,793-10,050 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 43
    - Nos. 10,051-10,153 (Box 57., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 10,157-10,260 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 10,261-10,400 (Folder 3)
  - Volume 44
    - Nos. 10,401-10,549 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 10,550-10,800 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 45
    - Nos. 10,801-10,923 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 10,924-11,080 (Box 58., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 11,081-11,250 (Folder 2)
  - Volume 46
    - Nos. 11,251-11,333 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 11,334-11,500 (Folder 4)
  - Volume 47
    - Nos. 11,501-11,640 (Folder 5)
    - Nos. 11,641-11,800 (Folder 6)
  - Volume 48 (Box 59.)
    - Nos. 11,801-12,007 (Folder 1)
    - Nos. 12,008-12,250 (Folder 2)
  - Volume 49
    - Nos. 12,251-12,383 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 12,384-12,506 (Folder 4)
  - Volume 50
    - Nos. 12,508-12,600 (Folder 5)
    - Nos. 12,601-12,824 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 12,825-13,094 (Box 60., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 13,095-13,250 (Folder 2)
  - Volume 51
    - Nos. 13,251-13,470 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 13,471-13,642 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 13,643-13,750 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 52
    - Nos. 13,751-13,968 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 13,969-14,072 (Folder 7)
  - Volume 52 (Contd.)
    - Nos. 14,073-14,150 (Box 61., Folder 1)
  - Volume 53
    - Nos. 14,151-14,566 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 14,567-14,652 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 14,653-14,750 (Folder 4)
  - Volume 54
    - Nos. 14,751-14,823 (Folder 5)
    - Nos. 14,824-14,907 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 14,908-15,000 (Box 62., Folder 1)
  - Volume 55
    - Nos. 15,001-15,096 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 15,097-15,169 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 15,170-15,250 (Folder 4)
  - Volume 56
    - Nos. 15,251-15,336 (Folder 5)
    - Nos. 15,337-15,423 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 15,424-15,500 (Box 63., Folder 1)
  - Volume 57
    - Nos. 15,501-15,574 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 15,575-15,616 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 15,617-15,635 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 15,636-15,660 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 66
    - Nos. 15,661-15,667 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 15,668-15,673 (Box 64., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 15,674-15,694 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 15,695-15,714 (Folder 3)
  - Volume 67
    - Nos. 623-7,998 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 8,004-11,368 (Folder 5)
- STATEMENTS
  - Volume 68
    - Nos. 15,717-15,766 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 15,767-15,773 (Box 65., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 15,774-15,790 (Folder 2)
  - Volume 69
    - Nos. 15,791-15,800 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 15,801-15,819 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 15,820-15,845 (Folder 5)
  - Volume 70
    - Nos. 15,846-15,863 (Folder 6)
    - Nos. 15,864-15,914 (Folder 7)
  - Volume 70 (Contd.)
    - Nos. 15,915-15,946 (Box 66., Folder 1)
  - Volume 71
    - Nos. 15,947-16,065 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 16,066-16,091 (Folder 3)
- DEPOSITS
  - Volume 72
    - Nos. 1,375-1,394 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 1,395-1,431 (Folder 5)
    - Nos. 1,432-1,450 (Folder 6)
    - No. 1,451 (Folder 7)
  - Volume 73 (Box 67.)
    - Nos. 1,452-1,491 (Folder 1)
    - Nos. 1,492-1,515 (Folder 2)
    - Nos. 1,516-1,527 (Folder 3)
  - Volume 74
    - Nos. 17,923-17,981 (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 17,982-18,065 (Folder 5)
      - Nos. 18,066-18,100 (Folder 6)
  - Volume 75
    - Nos. 18,101-18,184 (Folder 7)
    - Nos. 18,185-18,265 (Box 68., Folder 1)
    - Nos. 18,266-18,304 (Folder 2)
- MATERIALS FILED BY DOCUMENT NUMBER
  - Doc. No. 62c - "Polska Wschodnia w 1939-1940" (Eastern Poland in 1939-1940) (Folder 3)
  - Doc. No. 63 - "Stosunki Polsko-Rosyjskie od Chwili Wybuchu Wojny Niemecko-Rosyjskiej w Swietle Dokumentow" (Polish-Russian Relations from the Beginning of the German-Russian War According to Documents) (Folder 4)
  - Doc. No. 64 - "Miedzynardowe Prawo Wojenne" (International Military Law) (Folder 5)
  - Doc. No. 65b - "Ludzie Radzieccy Mowia..." (The Soviet People Speak...) (Folder 6)
  - Doc. No. 65c - "The Soviet People Speak" (Folder 7)
  - Doc. No. 66 - "Uwagi Na Margiuesie Referatu o Stosunkach Polsko-Rosyjskich" (Notes on the Report on Polish-Russian Relations) (Folder 8)
  - Doc. No. 67 - "Uwagi o Projekcie Dekretu Prezydenta Rzplitej o Organizacji Naczelnych Wladz Wojskowych w Czasie Wojny" (Notes on the Project of the Decree of the President of the Polish Republic Concerning the Organization of Supreme Military Authorities at the Time of War) (Folder 9)
  - Doc. No. 69b - "Higiena Pracy Na Terenie ZSSR" (Work Safety in the USSR) (Folder 10)
  - Doc. No. 70d - "Democracy and the Constitution of the USSR" (Folder 11)
  - Doc. No. 70i - "La Democrazia e l'URSS" (Democracy and the USSR) (Folder 12)
  - Doc. No. 76 - "Lenin o Rewolucji i Panstwie Proletariatu" (Lenin on Revolution and the Proletarian Government) (Folder 13)
  - Doc. No. 79b - "Praca w Panstwie Pracy" (Labor in the Country of Labor) (Folder 14)
  - Doc. No. 80a - "Ochrona Pracy w Panstwie Robotniczym" (The Protection of Labor in the Country of Workers) (Folder 15)
  - Doc. No. 83 - "Omowienie 'Anti-Semitism and the Jewish Question'" (Review of "Anti-Semitism and the Jewish Question") (Folder 16)
  - Doc. No. 84 - "Drogi Propagandy Sowieckiej w Palestynie" (The Paths of Soviet Propaganda in Palestine), 1943 (Box 69., Folder 1)
  - Doc. No. 85 - "Nastroje Sowieckie i Kommunistyczne w Palestynie" (Soviet and Communist Tendencies in Palestine) (Folder 2)
  - Doc. No. 86 - "Struktura Polityczna Spoleczenstwa Zydowskiego Palestyny" (The Political Structure of Jewish Society in Palestine) (Folder 3)
  - Doc. No. 87 - "Prasa Palestynska" (The Palestine Press) (Folder 4)
  - Doc. No. 88b - "Dzieje Posla Zydowskiego Miasta Lwowa, Emila Sommersteina" (Information on the Minister of the Jewish Section of Lvov, Emil Sommerstein) (Folder 5)
  - Doc. No. 89 - "Sprawa Erlicha i Altera" (The Affair of Erlich and Alter) (Folder 6)
  - Doc. No. 90 - "Spoleczenstwo Zydowskie w Polsce" (Jewish Society in Poland), 1943 (Folder 7)
  - Doc. No. 92 - "Sowiety Na Ziemach Polskich" (The Soviets on Polish Land) (Folder 8)
  - Doc. No. 93 - "Polityka Sowiecka Na Okupowanych Ziemach Polskich" (Soviet Policy in the Occupied Part of Poland) (Folder 9)
  - Doc. No. 94 - "Okupacja Wschodnich Ziem Polski Przez Zwiazek Sowiecki" (The Occupation of Eastern Poland by the Soviet Union) (Folder 10)
  - Doc. No. 95a - "Wilejka", prison (in Polish) (Folder 11)
  - Doc. No. 95e - "Wilejka", prison (Folder 12)
  - Doc. No. 96c - "Rosja - Polska" (Russia - Poland) (Folder 13)
  - Doc. No. 99 - "Gospodarka ZSSR w Swietle Hasel Komunistycznych" (The Economy of the USSR in the Light of Communist Slogans) (Folder 14)
  - Doc. No. 101a - "Notatka o Tworzeniu P.S.Z. w ZSSR" (A Note on the Organization of P.S.Z. in the USSR) (Folder 15)
  - Doc. No. 102 - "Konwencja Dotyczaca Praw i Zwyczajow Wojny Ladowej" (Convention Concerning the Laws and Customs of Land War) (Folder 16)
  - Doc. No. 103 - "Zbrodnie Stalina" (Stalin's Crimes) (Folder 17)
  - Doc. No. 104 - "System Prawa Miedzynarodowego" (The System of International Law) (Folder 18)
  - Doc. No. 108 - "Odpis Memorandum, Zlozonego w Ministerstwie Spraw Zagraniczynch R. P. w Londynie, 31/X/1942, Przez Ambassadora Bogomolowa" (Copy of the Memorandum Presented at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Repulic of Poland in London, 31/X/1942, by Ambassador Bogomlow) (Folder 19)
  - Doc. No. 109 - "Tekst Noty Ambasadora Bogomolowa do Ministra Spraw Zagranicznych R. P. z dn. 31 Pazdziernika 1942 roku" (Text of Ambassador Bogomolow's Notes to the Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Poland on October 31, 1942) (Folder 20)
  - Doc. No. 114 - "Dodatek Informacyjny - Wojny, Prowadzone Przez Rosje Ostatnich Stuleciach" (Information Supplement - Wars Carried on by Russia in the Past Centuries) (Folder 21)
  - Doc. No. 115 - "Warunki Zdrowowtne Czlowieka Pracy w ZSSR" (Sanitary Conditions of the Worker in the USSR) (Folder 22)
  - Doc. No. 116 - "Warnuki Zycia San. (Naszego) w ZSSR" (Sanitary Conditions for the Poles in the USSR) (Box 70., Folder 1)
  - Doc. No. 123a - "Sprawa Zolnierzy Polskich s ZSSR" (The Question of Polish Soldiers in the USSR) (Folder 2)
  - Doc. No. 129 - "Notatka o Sowieckich Akcjach w Palestynie" (Note on Soviet Activities in Palestine), 1942-43 (Folder 3)
  - Doc. No. 130a - "Prasa Zydowska w Palestynie" (The Jewish Press in Palestine) (Folder 4)
  - Doc. No. 131 - "Problem Powojennej Sytuacji Palestyny" (The Problem of Postwar Conditions in Palestine) (Folder 5)
  - Doc. No. 134 - "Polsko Zydowska Grupa Studiow" (Polish-Jewish Studies Group) (Folder 6)
  - Doc. No. 135 - "Wspolpraca Polsko-Zydowska" (Polish-Jewish Cooperation) (Folder 7)
  - Doc. No. 136 - "Uwagi Kierowonika Biura Studiow" (Notes of the Head of the Bureau of Studies) (Folder 8)
  - Doc. No. 138a - "Dzialalnosc Centralnego Urzedu Dla Osiedlania Zydow Niemieckich w Palestynie" (Operations of the Central Service for the Settlement of German Jews in Palestine), 1943 (Folder 9)
  - Doc. No. 139 - "Wrazenia z Pobytu w Palestynie" (Impressions from a Stay in Palestine) (Folder 10)
  - Doc. No. 140 - "Obserwacje i Wrazenia z Palestyny" (Observations and Impressions from Palestine) May 20, 1943 (Folder 11)
  - Doc. No. 141 - "Wytyczne Polityki Zydowskiej" (The Direction of Jewish Politics) (Folder 12)
  - Doc. No. 142 - "'Histadruth' i Jego Struktura Organizacyjna" ("Histadruth" and Its Organizational Structure), 1943 (Folder 13)
  - Doc. No. 143 - "Notatka w Sprawie Stronnictw Politycznych i Organizacyj w Niemczech" (A Note Concerning Political Parties and Organizations in Germany) (Folder 14)
  - Doc. No. 145 - "Rola Zydow Niemieckich w Palestynie" (The Role of German Jews in Palestine), 1943 (Folder 15)
  - Doc. No. 146 - "Proces o Kradziez Broni" (The Case of the Stolen Weapons), 1943 (Folder 16)
  - Doc. No. 147 - "Organizacje Zydowskie Na Terenie Palestyny" (Jewish Organizations in Palestine) (Folder 17)
  - Doc. No. 148 - "Prasa Palestynska" (Palestinian Press), September 1943 (Folder 18)
  - Doc. No. 149 - "Wspolpraca Polsko-Zydowska Na Terenie Palestyny" (Polish-Jewish Cooperation in Palestine), 1943 (Folder 19)
  - Doc. No. 150 - "Zagadnienie Dezercji Zolnierzy Zydow z Armii Polskiej" (The Question of Desertion by Jewish Soldiers from the Polish Army), October 1943 (Folder 20)
  - Doc. No. 151 - "W Sprawie Dezercji Zydow z Armii Polskiej" (On the Question of Desertion by Jews from the Polish Army) (Folder 21)
  - Doc. No. 154 - "Uwagi w Sprawie Ustosunkowania Sie Czynnikow Polskich Na Terenie Palestyny Do Majacego Sie Odbyc w Ameryce Swiatowego Kongresu Zydowstwa" (Comments Concerning the Attitude to Be Taken by Polish Authorities in Palestine toward the World Congress of Jewry to Be Held in America), 1944 (Folder 22)
  - Doc. No. 155 - "Rola Zydow Niemieckich w Palestynie i Ich Stosunek do Polski" (The Role of German Jews in Palestine and Their Attitude Toward Poland) (Folder 23)
  - Doc. No. 156 - "Wyjatek z Protokulu Posiedzenia Egzekutywy Agencji Zydowskiej dla Palestyny z dn. 17/XII/1942 r." (Excerpt from the Minutes of the Meeting of the Executive Committee of the Jewish Agency for Palestine, 17/XII/1942) (Folder 24)
  - Doc. No. 157 - "Depesza Prof. Grzybowskiego" (Telegram of Prof. Grzybowski) (Folder 25)
  - Doc. No. 158 - "Sprawa Zydowska w Palestynie Jako Teren Obserwacji Polityki Swiatowej Mocarstw" (The Jewish Question as an Observation Point of Politics of the World Powers) (Folder 26)
  - Doc. No. 159 - "Zwiazek Zydow Krajow Baltyckich" (Union of Jews of The Baltic Countries), August 5, 1943 (Folder 27)
  - Doc. No. 160 - "Dyskusja Na Temat Oblicza Ideowo-Politycznego Grupy 'Alija Chadasza'" (Discussion on the Topic of the Ideological-Political Make-up of the "Alija Chadasza" Group), August 17, 1943 (Folder 28)
  - Doc. No. 161 - "Pobyt Majskiego w Palestynie" (Majski's Stay in Palestine) (Folder 29)
  - Doc. No. 162 - "W Sprawie Rewizji Kibucu Hulda" (On the Matter of the Inspection of the Hulda Kibbutz) (Folder 30)
  - Doc. No. 163 - "W Sprawie Rewizji Kibucu Hulda" (On the Matter of the Inspection of the Hulda Kibbutz) (Box 71., Folder 1)
  - Doc. No. 164 - "W Sprawie Rewizji Kibucu Chulta" (On the Matter of the Inspection of the Chulta Kibbutz) (Folder 2)
  - Doc. No. 165 - "W Sprawie Rewizji w Ramat Hakowesz" (On the Matter of the Inspection of Ramat Hakowesz) (Folder 3)
  - Doc. No. 166 - "W Sprawie Rewizji Po Kibucach" (On the Matter of the Inspection of Kibbutzes) (Folder 4)
  - Doc. No. 167 - "Sprawy Zydowskie w Palestynie" (Jewish Affairs in Palestine), November 25, 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Doc. No. 168 - "List Konsula Seidemana Dotyczacy Dezercji" (Letter of Consul Seideman about Desertion), November 28, 1943 (Folder 6)
  - Doc. No. 169a - "Zestawienie Wypadkow Polit. Zyd., 142/43" (Compilation of Jewish Political Events, 1942/43) (Folder 7)
  - Doc. No. 170 - "Notatka o Dzialalnosci Partii Kom. Palest." (Note on the Activities of the Palestinian Communist Party) (Folder 8)
  - Doc. No. 171a - Notatka o Rozmowach Ben Eliazera" (Note on the Conversations of Ben Eliazer) (Folder 9)
  - Doc. No. 172 - "Dzialaln. Amer. Jewish Warfare Commeet." (Activities of the American Jewish Warfare Committee) (Folder 10)
  - Doc. No. 173 - "Notatka o Dzialaln. Rabina M. Berlina" (Note on the Activities of Rabbi M. Berlin) (Folder 11)
  - Doc. No. 174 - "Wspolpraca z Organ. Rewizjon. w USA" (Cooperation with the Inspection Organization in the USA) (Folder 12)
  - Doc. No. 175 - "Notatka o Wspolpracy z Org. Rewizj. w Pal." (Note on Cooperation with Inspection Organizations in Palestine) (Folder 13)
  - Doc. No. 176 - "Notatka o Przemyslowcach Naftowych" (Note on the Oil Industries), January 19, 1944 (Folder 14)
  - Doc. No. 177 - "Notatka o Wspolpracy z Centrum Informac." (Note on Cooperation with the Information Center) (Folder 15)
  - Doc. No. 178 - "Notatka o Antysemityzmie Wsrod Uchodz." (Note on Anitsemitism among the Refugees) (Folder 16)
  - Doc. No. 179 - "Notatka o Dzialalnosci Eliazera" (Note on the Activities of Eliazer) (Folder 17)
  - Doc. No. 180 - "Notatka o Sytuacji Zydowstwa Europejsk." (Note on the Condition of European Jewry) (Folder 18)
  - Doc. No. 181 - "Notatka w Zwiazku z Wyjazdem Eliazera" (Note in Connection with Eliazer's Trip), February 14, 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Doc. No. 182 - "Notatka o Dzialalnosci Eliazera w Palestynie" (Note on the Activities of Eliazer in Palestine), February 14, 1944 (Folder 20)
  - Doc. No. 183 - "Notatka o Procesie Hajdukiewicza" (Note on the Trial of Hajdukiewicz), March 3, 1944 (Folder 21)
  - Doc. No. 184 - "Notatka o Przybyciu z Rosji Deleg. 'Gerojow'" (Note on the Arrival of the Delegation of "Heroes" from Russia), March 6, 1944 (Folder 22)
  - Doc. No. 185 - "Declaration of Inspection in Connection with Bombing Attacks", March 31, 1944 (Folder 23)
  - Doc. No. 185a - "Oswiadczenie Rewizjon. w Zwiazku z Zamachem Bombowym" (Declaration of Inspection in Connection with Bombing Attacks), March 31, 1944 (Folder 24)
  - Doc. No. 186 - "O Antysemityzmie w Wojsku Polskim" (On Antisemitism in the Polish Military) (Folder 25)
  - Doc. No. 187 - "Od Czarnej Zarazy Po Dzien Dzisiejszy" (From the Black Plague until the Present Day), March 12, 1943 (Folder 26)
  - Doc. No. 189 - "Sprawozdanie Antyfaszystowskiego Komitetu w Kujbyszewie", May 1943 (Folder 27)
  - Doc. No. 191c - "Do Zydow Amerykanskich" (To the American Jews), July 17, 1943 (Folder 28)
  - Doc. No. 193 - "Gdzie Jest Narod Zydowski w Ich Polsce" (Where Are the Jewish People in Their Poland), August 15, 1943 (Folder 29)
  - Doc. No. 195 - "Sjonizm a Rosja Sowiecka" (Zionism in Soviet Russia), September 1943 (Folder 30)
  - Doc. No. 196 - "Poklosie Wizyty Pfeffera i Michoelsa" (Results of the Visit of Pfeffer and Michoels), September 19, 1943 (Folder 31)
  - Doc. No. 198 - "Polityka Becka w Nowym Wydaniu" (Beck's Politics in the New Edition) (Folder 32)
  - Doc. No. 200 - "O Dzialalnosci Ligi V - w Prasy Sowieckiej" (On the Activities of the League V - From the Soviet Press), February 2, 1944 (Folder 33)
  - Doc. No. 202a - "Oswiadczenie Molotowa w Teorii i w Praktyce" (Molotov's Statement in Theory and in Practice), February 6, 1944 (Folder 34)
  - Doc. No. 203 - "Towarzyszu Eliazer - Dosc!" (Comrade Eliazer - Enough!), February 18, 1944 (Folder 35)
  - Doc. No. 204 - "Zapomnialem Nazwiska" (I Forgot the Name) (Folder 36)
  - Doc. No. 205 - "Uchodzcy Zydzi w Rosji" (Jewish Refugees in Russia), February 22, 1944 (Folder 37)
  - Doc. No. 206 - "Chamberlain Umarl - Ale Polityka Monachijska Pozostala" (Chamberlain Has Died - But Munich Politics Continue) (Folder 38)
  - Doc. No. 207 - "Wybory w Kraju Sowietow" (Elections in the Country of Soviets), March 31, 1944 (Folder 39)
  - Doc. No. 209 - "Ostatnia Sposobnosc" (Last Opportunity) (Folder 40)
  - Doc. No. 211a - "Odglosy w Diasporze w Zwiazku z Ustanowieniem Orderu Imienia Chmeilnickiego" (Echoes in Diaspora Concerning the Creation of the Order of the Name Chmielnicki) (Folder 41)
  - Doc. No. 212 - "Wprowadzilismy w Blad Polakow" (We Mislead the Poles), April 12, 1944 (Folder 42)
  - Doc. No. 213 - "Rzecz Wazna i Drugorzedna" (An Important and Secondary Matter), April 16, 1944 (Folder 43)
  - Doc. No. 215 - "Tysiace Zydow Ginie z Glodu i Zimna w Stepach Sybiru" (A Thousand Jews Die from Starvation and Cold in the Steppes of Siberia), April 19, 1943 (Folder 44)
  - Doc. No. 216 - "Komitet Pieciu Dla Odbudowy Ruin w Rosji" (Committee Five for the Reconstruction of the Destruction in Russia), April 19, 1944 (Folder 45)
  - Doc. No. 217 - "Los Idealistow w Kraju Soweickim" (The Fate of Idealists in the Country of The Soviets), April 21, 1944 (Folder 46)
  - Doc. No. 218 - "Nie Przesadzajcie!" (Don't Exaggerate!), May 2, 1944 (Folder 47)
  - Doc. No. 219 - "Sem, Cham i Jafet" (Sem, Cham and Jafet), May 7, 1944 (Folder 48)
  - Doc. No. 231 - "Miedzy Algierem i Ankara" (Between Algeria and Ankara), November 1943 (Folder 49)
  - Doc. No. 232a - "Ruch Wolnej Austrii i Akcje Niemickie Na Wschodzie" (The Movement of Free Austria and German Actions in the East) (Folder 50)
  - Doc. No. 238 - "Azerbejdzancycy w Iranie" (Azerbedjanians in Iran) (Folder 51)
  - Doc. No. 239 - "Emigracja Ormianska w Iranie" (Armenian Emigration to Iran) (Folder 52)
  - Doc. No. 241 - "Wyjatki z Raportu z Bejrutu to MSZ" (Excerts from a Report from Beirut to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs), November 12, 1943 (Folder 53)
  - Doc. No. 250a - "Sytuacja Polityczna w Swiecie Arabskim" (The Political Situation in the Arab World), December 15, 1944 (Folder 54)
  - Doc. No. 255 - "Uwagi o Antypolskiej Propagandzie ze Strony Zydow Przyblych z Polski" (Comments on the Anti-Polish Propaganda On the Part of Jews Arriving from Poland), February 14, 1944 (Folder 55)
  - Doc. No. 257 - "Kolektywijacja w ZSSR" (Collectivization in the USSR) (Folder 56)
  - Doc. No. 258 - "Religia, Syjonizm i Jezyk Hebrajski w Rosji Sowieckiej" (Religion, Zionism and the Hebrew Language in Soviet Russia), June 12, 1944 (Folder 57)
  - Doc. No. 264 - "Aktywnosc Amerykanska Na Bliskim i Srednem Wschodzie" (American Activity in the Near and Middle East) (Folder 58)
  - Doc. No. 265 - "Praca Propagandowa Na Terenie Iranu" (Propaganda Work in Iran) (Folder 59)
  - Doc. No. 278 - "Rosja Na Bliskim i Srodkowym Wschodzie" (Russia in the Near and Central East), June 1943 (Folder 60)
  - Doc. No. 279 - "Rosyjska Ekspansja Gospodarcza Na Srodkowym Wschodzie" (Russian Economic Expansion in the Central East) (Folder 61)
  - Doc. No. 281 - "Middle East Supply Centre i Jego Rola W Powojennej Europie" (Middle East Supply Centre and Its Role in Postwar Europe) (Folder 62)
  - Doc. No. 282e - "Problem Rosyjski w Polityce Polskiej" (The Russian Problem in Polish Politics) (Folder 63)
  - Doc. No. 283 - "Uwagi o Polityce Angielskiej i Sowieckiej" (Comments on English and Soviet Politics) (Folder 64)
  - Doc. No. 289 - "W Sprawie Dezercji Zydow z Armii Polskiej" (Concerning Jewish Desertions from the Polish Army) (Folder 65)
  - Doc. No. 290 - "O Dzialalnosci P.K.P. Wsrod Arabow" (On the Activities of the P.K.P. Among the Arabs) (Folder 66)
  - Doc. No. 294 - "Sytuacja Polityczna w Kurdystanie" (The Political Situation in Kurdistan) (Folder 67)
  - Doc. No. 298 - "Iran Polnocny i Stanowisko Sowietow" (Northern Iran and the Attitude of the Soviets), August 1943 (Folder 68)
  - Doc. No. 334 - "Przemysl w ZSSR" (Industry in the USSR), Dcember 1942 (Folder 69)
  - Doc. No. 335 - "Transport w ZSSR" (Transportation in the USSR) (Folder 70)
  - Doc. No. 336 - "Kwestia Nardowosciowa w ZSSR" (The Question of Nationality in the USSR) (Folder 71)
  - Doc. No. 337 - "Rolnictwo w ZSSR" (Farming in the USSR) (Folder 72)
  - Doc. No. 338 - "Propaganda Komunistyczna w Iraku" (Communist Propaganda in Iraq), April 15, 1943 (Folder 73)
  - Doc. No. 339 - "Wplywy Sowieckie i Dzialalnosc Komnistyczna w Iraku" (Soviet Influences and Communist Activity in Iraq) (Box 72., Folder 1)
  - Doc. No. 340 - "Drogi Propagandy Sowieckiej w Palestynie" (The Paths of Soviet Propaganda in Palestine), February 17, 1943 (Folder 2)
  - Doc. No. 341 - "Propaganda Sowiecka w Pasie Neutralnym Iranu" (Soviet Propaganda in the Neutral Zone of Iran), June 1943 (Folder 3)
  - Doc. No. 342 - "Notatka o Sowieckiej Propagandzie i Akcjach Politycznych w Palestynie" (Note on Soviet Propaganda and Political Actions in Palestine), January 1943 (Folder 4)
  - Doc. No. 343 - "Nastroje Sowieckie i Komunistyczne w Palestynie" (Soviet and Communist Mood in Palestine), January 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Doc. No. 344 - "Rosyjski Ruch Wyzwolenczy i Stosunek Stalina do Tego Ruchu" (The Russian Liberation Movement and Stalin's attitude Toward It) (Folder 6)
  - Doc. No. 345 - "Rosyjski Ruch Wyzwolenczy Gen. Wlasowa i Stosunek do Niego Prasy Bularskiej" (The Russian Liberation Movement of General Vlasov and the Attitude Toward It of the Bulgarian Press) (Folder 7)
  - Doc. No. 346 - "Objazd Rosyjskich Ziem Wyzwolonych Przez Gen Wlasowa" (A Tour of the Russian Lands Liberated by General Vlasov) (Folder 8)
  - Doc. No. 347 - "Propaganda Sowiecka Na Terenie Syrii" (Soviet Propaganda in Syria), March 1943 (Folder 9)
  - Doc. No. 501 - "Rosja a Kwestia Zydowska" (Russia and the Jewish Question) (Folder 10)
  - Doc. No. 502 - "Nasze Wlasne Obliczenia" (Our Own Calculations), July 20, 1944 (Folder 11)
  - Doc. No. 503 - "Armia Czerwona Doszla do 'Linii Curzona'" (The Red Army has Reached the "Curzon Line"), July 20, 1944 (Folder 12)
  - Doc. No. 504 - "Wobec Walk w Krajach Baltyckich" (In View of the Battles in the Baltic Countries), July 17, 1944 (Folder 13)
  - Doc. No. 505 - "Notatki Anti-Ma 'Murzyn' Czerwony i Jego Skora" (Notes of the Anti-Ma - The Red "Negroe" and His Skin), July 17, 1944 (Folder 14)
  - Doc. No. 506 - "Komunisci Libanscy a Dzielo Syjonistyczne" (Communist Lebanese and the Zionist Question), June 20, 1944 (Folder 15)
  - Doc. No. 507 - "Czyny i Marzenia Sosnkowskiego" (The Deeds and Aspirations of General Sosnkowski), June 8, 1944 (Folder 16)
  - Doc. No. 508 - "Nowa Mowa w Ustach Komunistow Zydowskich" (New Language in the Mouths of Jewish Communists), July 7, 1944 (Folder 17)
  - Doc. No. 509 - "Antysemityzm w Polskiej Armii" (Antisemitism in the Polish Army), May 25, 1944 (Folder 18)
  - Doc. No. 510 - "Tajemnica Sily Moralnej Kraju Sowietow" (The Secret of Moral Strength in the Country of Soviets), May 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Doc. No. 511 - "Z Plenum Zydowskiego Komitetu Antyfaszystowskiego" (From the Plenary Session of the Jewish Antifascist Committee), May 1944 (Folder 20)
  - Doc. No. 513 - "Nowa Rewolucja w Rosji" (New Revolution in Russia), June 28, 1944 (Folder 21)
  - Doc. No. 515d - "Zolnierze Polscy w Niewoli Sowieckiej" (Soldiers of Poland in Soviet Captivity) (Folder 22)